Sneha Singhal

Chartered Accountant

Personal Info

Email

sneha.singhal1392@gmail.com

Phone

+91-9928400660

Skills

- Completed 100 Hrs compulsory IT training and General Management and Communication Skills Training conducted by ICAI.
- Good Oratory and Management skills.
- * Keen learner and temperament to handle pressure.
- ❖ Won various awards in cocurricular activities.
- * Team player and Dedicated.

Software

MS Excel and MS Word



Tally, Easy Audit, **Monitor Plus**



Finacle and Intellect



Languages

English Hindi



Gujarati

Driven Chartered Accountant with 2.6 years of experience specialization in accounting, auditing, credit monitoring for diverse organizations. Advanced knowledge of generally accepted accounting principles and practices. Fosters transparency, understanding and ownership of financial reports and financial and operational metrics across organization. Thorough understanding of applicable laws, regulations, public finance and external reporting.

Work History

Sep 2021 - present

Contractor (Financial Advisory-Forensic & Dispute Services)

DKMS & Co in association with Deloitte, Ahmedabad

- · Assisting the engagement team with the work procedures to be performed on various projects.
- · Performing forensic examination of disputed documents to evaluate the quantum of frauds involved.

Nov 2018 - Feb 2020

Deputy Manager (Corporate Credit Monitoring Deptt.)

Axis Bank Ltd, Ahmedabad

- Worked as Corporate Credit Monitoring Official.
- · Analyzing the Stock Statements and Financial Statements of the Corporate Borrowers.
- Performing Short review of New Accounts and Escrow account review: Analyzing % of Sales routing, No. of defaults made, and Overall conduct of the account.
- Reviewing Unit and Collateral Inspection Reports of the Borrowers.
- Reviewing Valuation Reports, NEC, Title Search, and Legal Audit Reports.
- Reviewing and analyzing Stock Audit Reports and ROC search reports.
- Monitoring the Drawing Power based on various analyses.
- Performed Process Control Audit of a CBO Operating Unit, solely.
- · Reviewing all the Covenants in the Sanction Letters and assuring the compliances.
- · Monitoring end-use of funds.

Aug 2017

- Aug 2018

Audit Manager

M/S C.R. Sharedalal & Co., Ahmedabad

- * Reviewing & Monitoring Accounting work with statutory compliances.
- * Reviewing & Monitoring Auditing work with Company law and statutory compliances.

Statutory Audits:

Preparation of Audit plan, Vouching, Verification, Stock verification, Ledger scrutiny as a part of both corporate & non-corporate entities. Finalization of books of accounts & preparation of Balance Sheets & Profit/Loss Accounts of companies and partnerships firms such as:

- > Company Audits :
- 1. Navil Laboratories Pvt Ltd
- 2. Yash Builders
- 3. Gujarat Institute of Housing & Estate Development
- 4. Laxmi Jewellers Private Limited
- > Partnership firms & Proprietorship Firm :
- 1. Het Graphics
- 2. Siddhi Vinayak Hospital

Tax Audits:

-Preparation of Tax Audit Reports for various assesses including companies, Partnership firms, individuals, etc.

Aug 2011

Article Assistant

- Aug 2014 M/S Mehta Lodha & Co., Ahmedabad

- * Reviewing & Monitoring Accounting work with statutory compliances.
- Reviewing & Monitoring Auditing work with Company law and statutory compliances.
 - Electrotherm India Ltd.
- Income Tax Returns Filling of individual and partnership firm
- Audit of Trusts
 - Hathisingh ki wadi

Education

May 2017 Chartered Accountancy

ICAI, Ahmedabad

Percentage Obtained: 53%

Mar 2013 **B.Com**

R.J. Tibrewal College of Commerce, Ahmedabad

Percentage Obtained: 66%

Mar 2010 **H.S.C**

C.B.S.E H.G. International School, Aburoad

Percentage Obtained: 73%

Mar 2008 S.S.C

C.B.S.E St. Anselm's Sr. Sec School, Aburoad

Percentage Obtained: 83%